Guide to the Alonzo Barton Hepburn Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Alonzo Barton Hepburn Papers,
1886-1920.
Hepburn, A. Barton (Alonzo Barton), 1846-1922.
ca. 1,100 items (6 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078887
Biographical Note
Banker, philanthropist, Trustee of Columbia University, 1917-1922. (LL.D., 1911).
Scope and Content
Correspondence, letter books, manuscripts, typescripts, notes, galley proofs, reports, banking records, pamphlets, and other printed materials. The so-called "private" letter books contain copies of outgoing personal and business letters, April 1914-Jan. 1918. The remaining correspondence files relate to the writing of Hepburn's two books History of Coinage and Currency in the United States (New York, 1903) and A History of Coinage and Currency in the United States.(New York, 1915); to his activities in the fields of finance and money, such as the Pan-American Finance Commission (1915), the New York State Governor's Securities Commission (1920), and the Federal Milk Commission (1917); and his files regarding the establishment of the Columbia-Presbyterian Medical Center, 1918. Also, manuscripts, typescripts, notes, and galley proofs for the two books that he wrote; and six bank examiner's books used by Hepburn while he was U.S. Bank Examiner for New York, 1888-1892.
Subjects
Columbia-Presbyterian Medical Center.; Banks and banking--New York (State)--New York.; Finance.; Medical centers.; New York State Governor's Securities Commission.; Federal Milk Commission.; Pan-American Finance Commission.; Bankers.2lcsh; Philanthropists.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room. This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1953 M-53 Cushman, Cordelia Gift
- Box List
  - Letter books: (Box 1)
    - April 19l4-April 1915 (Box 1)
    - October 1916-January 1918 (Box 1)
  - History of Coinage and Currency in the United States (1903) (Box 2)
  - History of Currency in the United States (1915) (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Files on Money and Finance (including Pan-American Finance Commission, N. Y. State Governor's Securities Commission, etc.) (Box 4)
  - Federal Milk Commission (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Additional typescripts &manuscripts re: history of coinage &currency (Box 6)
  - U. S. Bank Examiner's Books, 1889-1891 (6 volumes; volume 6 is blank) (Box 6)
  - Order book Canton, N.Y., 1886 (Box 6)